// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "When a crystal of potassium pwemanganate is placed at the bottom of water in a beaker ,the water in whole beakers turns purple on its own.Its an example of ",
    answer: "diffusion",
    options: [
      "difussion",
     "distribution",
      "intrusion",
      "effusion "
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which one of the following statement is true in respect to fluids?",
    answer: "gases and liquids behave as fluids",
    options: [
      "only gases liquids are fluids",
      "only gases are fluids",
      "gases and solids behave as fluids",
      "gases and liquids behave as fluids"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In addition to speed, what else is needed to predict a object's position",
    answer: "Direction of speed",
    options: [
      "Distance travelled",
      "Displacment",
      "Speed",
      "Direction of speed"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What type of motion is exhibited by a free falling body?",
    answer: "Accelerated Motion",
    options: [
      "Accelerated Motion",
      "Uniform Motion",
      "Circular Motion",
      "Uniform speed"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "The numerical ratio of displacement to distance for moving object is:",
    answer: "equal to or less than 1",
    options: [
      "equal to or more than one",
      "equal to or less than 1",
      "always less than 1",
      "always more than 1"
    ]
  },
     {
     numb: 6,
     question: "A boy is sitting on a merry-go-round which is moving with a constant speed of 10m/s. This means the boy is:",
     answer: "in accelerated motion",
     options: [
      "at rest",
      "in uniform motion",
      "in uniform velocity",
      "in acclerated motion"
     ]
   },
   {
    numb: 7,
    question: " The speed of a moving object is 0.06m/s.This speed is equal to:",
    answer: "0.216km/h",
    options: [
     "2.16km/h",
     "1.08km/h",
     "0.216hm/h",
     "0.0216m/h"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following is correct regarding velocity and speed of a moving body-",
    answer: "velocity of a moving body is speed in a given direction",
    options: [
     "velocity of a moving body is always higher than its speed ",
     "velocity of a moving body is speed in a given diretion ",
     "speed of a moving body is velocity in a given direction ",
     " speed of a moving body is always higher than its velocity"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following could not be a unit of speed?",
    answer: "s/m",
    options: [
     "km/h",
     "mm/s",
     "s/m",
     "m/s"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following could not be a unit of acceleration?",
    answer: "cm/s",
    options: [
     "km/s^2",
     "m/s^2",
     "cm/s",
     "cm/s^2"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "What does not changes continuously in uniform circular motion?",
    answer: "speed",
    options: [
     "speed",
     "velocity",
     "accleration",
     "direction of motion"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Name the quantity which is measured by the area occupied under the v-t graph.",
    answer: "Distance travelled",
    options: [
     "force",
     "velocity",
     "speed",
     "Distance travelled"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "What does the slope of speed time graph indicate?",
    answer: "Acceleration",
    options: [
     "Speed",
     "Acceleration",
     "Distance travelled",
     "Force"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "2as=v^2-u^2 what does s stand here for?",
    answer: "displacement",
    options: [
     "speed",
     "displacement",
     "distance",
     "velocity"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "if body moves with a unifom velocity, its accleration is",
    answer: "zero",
    options: [
     "uniform",
     "non uniform",
     "zero",
     "qual to velocity"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "The slope of a distance time indicates ________ of a body",
    answer: "speed",
    options: [
     "work done",
     "displacement",
     "distance",
     "speed"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "s=v^2-u^2/2a is this equation correct? ",
    answer: "true",
    options: [
     "true",
     "false"
    
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "If the displacement of a object is proportional to time^2, then object is moving with:",
    answer: "uniform accleration",
    options: [
     "uniform speed",
     "uniform accleration",
     "uniform velocity",
     "non uniform speed"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "It is possible for something to accelerate but not change its speed if its moving in a ",
    answer: "circular motion",
    options: [
     "circular motion",
     "linear motion",
     "uniform motion",
     "non uniform motion"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Earth moves round the sun with uniform velocity",
    answer: "False",
    options: [
     "True",
     "False"
    ]
  },

  
];